Mauricio Gonzalez

Barva, Heredia, Costa Rica

Mobile: 87075176 • Email: gonzalez.araya.mauricio@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mgonzaleza/

Web: https://mgonzaleza.github.io



Professional Summary

Driven professional with broad technical skill-set, very strong attention to detail, and over 10 years experience in front-end and back-end web development. Able to multitask and juggle multiple pressing projects simultaneously. On top of the latest trends and technologies. Ability to improvise, troubleshoot, take ownership, and learn new skills on the job.

Experience

Freelancer January 2017 – currently

Clients: CodeEngineStudio

Project: Migration of Angular/MongoDB app from Parse Server(retired service) to AWS/DynamoDB. REST API built in Rails to replace the Parse endpoints.

Havas Magma, Sr. Software Developer

July 2016 - December 2016

Responsible for all stages of website creations for clientele. From initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management of websites.

OfficeSpace Software, Ruby Developer

December 2014 - May 2016

Developed new functionality as well as maintained the product with the aid of Agile processes. Technologies used included: Rails, Rspec/Capybara, ReactJS, MariaDB

Clients include: Dropbox, Toronto Public Health, PetSmart

Blue Fountain Media, Web Developer

October 2013 - November 2014

I was part of a remote distributed team of developers (USA, Argentina, Portugal and Costa Rica). Developed frontend and backend work with: Wordpress, Magento, Drupal and a proprietary CMS based on Yii.

Clients include: BaldorFood, AOL.

Critical Mass LATAM, Developer/Tech Lead

October 2008 – September 2013

Assisted with managing a team of 15+ peers. Direct contact with clients and provided technical estimations. Interviewing. Project oversight.

Responsible for all stages of website creations for clientele. From initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management of websites

Clients include: Clorox, Infiniti, Adidas, Mattel, ATT, Best Buy.

Awards: Employee of the year 2011.

Education

Scrum Master Certified currently

Master in Web Systems

Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica currently

Bachelor of Science: Systems Engineering.

Universidad Nacional de Costa Rica 2015

Skills

Ruby (Rails, RSpec, Capybara)

PHP (Laravel, Wordpress, Magento)

Databases (MySQL, MongoDB, DynamoDB, MS SQL, PostgreSQL)

Javascript (Vanilla, React, Angular)

Web (HTML, CSS, Responsive design, hybrid mobile apps)

Languages

Native: Spanish.

Fluent: English.

Beginner: German (A2).

Interests

Reading

Tennis

All things Sci-Fi